Guide to the Film programs from East Germany, 1953-1978
Department of Special Collections
Film programs from East Germany,
1953-1978
Special Collections M0771
5 linear ft. (ca. 1700 items)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1995.
Scope and Content
Ca. 1700 film programs with the titles Progress Film Illustrierte (1953-1957) and Progress Film Programm (1957-1978, from #63/66 with additional title "Film für Sie"), both published by VEB Progress Film Vertrieb, Berlin, mostly 2 pages. The collection includes loose leaf index (ca. 28 pages) of films from 1969-1974, ca. 50 programs for children's films (1967-1970) as well as ca. 30 magazine-style catalogs for GDR and USSR feature film and made-for-TV film festivals. There are also approx. 85 volumes of the magazine Treffpunkt Kino (1970-1977), published by Progress Film Verleih Berlin.
Programs include such information as cast; director; film's country of origin; voiceover credits; photos; and plot summary, largely from an anticapitalist or antifascist perspective. Films represented are western as well as east bloc productions; some Asian films included. Genres range from romances, melodramas, light comedies, musicals, opera, and literary adaptations to westerns, adventure, spy stories, cold war themes, class relations and diatribes against capitalism. Children's films range from feature films to cartoons and hand puppet films and are largely Czech or East German in origin.
Western productions include American films such as Manche mögen's heiß (39/68), and Weißer Terror (125/65) about race relations and the Ku Klux Klan, as well as Urteil von Nürnberg (134/63). There are programs for English, Scottish, French, Italian, Austrian, as well as East German, Russian-Soviet, Georgian-Soviet, Yugoslavian, Czech, Hungarian, Rumanian, Chinese, Vietnamese, and Korean films. Some collaborations are also included, such as French-Swedish and German [DEFA]-Swedish. Representative films from the east bloc are those extolling communism and socialism, including the Soviet production Das russische Wunder (31/63), as well as literary adaptations of Russian classics, including Krieg und Frieden (11/67 and 25/67). There are also many examples of films that expose the evils of western society, such as the Italian film Garantiert Jungfrau (101/69).
The magazine Treffpunkt Kino includes such features as descriptive reviews of films; film credits; Tatsachen und Tendenzen - DEFA in Potsdam-Babelsberg; Neue Kinderfilme; DEFA-Report; Auslandbericht.
Access Terms
DEFA; Motion pictures--East Germany.; Film fur Sie.; Progress Film Illustrierte.; Progress Film Programm.; Treffpunkt Kino.
Container List
- Progress Film Illustrierte 16/53-58/53 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  3 programs
- Progress Film Illustrierte 37/54-90/54 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  15 programs
- Progress Film Illustrierte 2/55-68/55 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Progress Film Illustrierte 70/55-102/55 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  20 programs
- Progress Film Illustrierte 2/56-44/56 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  18 programs
- Progress Film Illustrierte 45/56-74/56 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Progress Film Illustrierte 76/56-113/56 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Progress Film Illustrierte 1/57-29/57 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  14 programs
- Progress Film Illustrierte 30/57-68/57 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Progress Film Programm 57/57-128/57 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  30 programs
- Progress Film Programm 9/58-49/58 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Progress Film Programm 51/58-96/58 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Progress Film Programm 97/58-128/58 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  11 programs
- Progress Film Programm 3/59-76/59 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Progress Film Programm 79/59-129/59 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  19 programs
- Progress Film Programm 8/60-41/60 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Progress Film Programm 43/60-73/60 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Progress Film Programm 74/60-100/60 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Progress Film Programm 101/60-134/60 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  23 programs
- Progress Film Programm 1/61-36/61 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  25 programs
- Progress Film Programm 38/61-113/61 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Progress Film Programm 1/62-35/62 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  17 programs
- Progress Film Programm 36/62-114/62 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  16 programs
- Progress Film Programm 3/63-134/63 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Progress Film Programm 1/64-154/64 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Progress Film Programm 4/65-65/65 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Progress Film Programm 66/65-96/65 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Progress Film Programm 102/65-129/65 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Progress Film Programm 13/66-55/66 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Progress Film Programm 58/66-93/66 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Progress Film Programm 98/66-120/66 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Progress Film Programm 1/67-23/67 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Progress Film Programm 24/67-52/67 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Progress Film Programm 53/67-77/67 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Progress Film Programm 78/67-98/67 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Progress Film Programm 98/67-104/67 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  13 programs
- Progress Film Programm 105/67-121/67 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  21 programs
- Progress Film Programm 1/68-33/68 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Progress Film Programm 34/68-65/68 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Progress Film Programm 66/68-95/68 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Progress Film Programm 96/68-118/68 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  24 programs
- Progress Film Programm 1/69-30/69 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Progress Film Programm 31/69-59/69 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Progress Film Programm 60/69-88/69 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Progress Film Programm 89/69-121/69 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  31 programs
- Progress Film Programm 1/70-28/70 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  28 programs
- Progress Film Programm 29/70-52/70 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Progress Film Programm 53/70-76/70 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Progress Film Programm 2/71-32/71 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Progress Film Programm 33/71-50/71 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Progress Film Programm 51/71-70/71 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Progress Film Programm 1/72-29/72 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Progress Film Programm 30/72-49/72 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Progress Film Programm 50/72-71/72 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Progress Film Programm 72/72-96/72 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Progress Film Programm 1/73-26/73 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Progress Film Programm 27/73-55/73 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Progress Film Programm 56/73-82/73 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Progress Film Programm 83/73-105/73 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Progress Film Programm 1/74-26/74 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Progress Film Programm 27/74-50/74 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Progress Film Programm 51/74-85/74 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Progress Film Programm 1/75-30/75 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  27 programs
- Progress Film Programm 1/76-30/76 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Progress Film Programm 1/77-23/77 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Progress Film Programm 24/77-47/77 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Progress Film Programm 2/78-29/78 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- 15 assorted catalogs 1970-1975 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- 14 assorted catalogs 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Progress Film Programm 1978, #1-7, [booklets] (Box 5, Folder 11)
- loose leaf index for Progress Film Programme 1969-1974. Sozialistische Filmkunst pamphlet and Studiokino pamphlets 8/75-12/75 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- K16/17[sic]-K24/67 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  6 children's film programs
- K1/68-K18/68 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  17 children's film programs
- K1/69-K14/69 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  13 children's film programs
- K1/70-K16/70 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Kinder Treffpunkt Kino Filmkalender 1973 (Box 6)
- Treffpunkt Kino A/70-K/70, (10 magazines) (Box 6)
- A/71-M/71, (11 magazines) (Box 6)
- A/72-L/72, (11 magazines) (Box 6)
- Festival des sowjetischen Films im Kino und Fernsehen der DDR. Aus Anlaß des 50. Jahrestages der Bildung der UdSSR 1972. (Box 6)
- Treffpunkt Kino 1/73-12/73 (Box 7)
  (10 magazines)
- Treffpunkt Kino 1/74-12/74 (Box 7)
  (12 magazines).
- Treffpunkt Kino 1/75-12/75 (Box 8)
  (12 magazines)
- Treffpunkt Kino 1-2/76-12/76 (Box 8)
  (11 magazines).
- Treffpunkt Kino 1/77-9/77 (Box 9)
  (7 magazines).